# **CURRICULUM VITAE**



Johan O. Holmberg

# Introduction

I am an experienced business analyst and business developer, with almost 20 years working experience in international environments. With a background working in both private and public sector, including universities, I have a very good network globally from field workers to members of governments, and am well positioned to engage in complex processes, especially related to investments, funding and developement of projects and companies.

Looking for new opportunities on a full time or part time basis, as I am looking at settling down and be a passive shareholder and partner in some ventures, and downsize my engagement in others, as I am relocating for family reasons.

# **Experience**

# Ariana group of companies, Director and COO 2013 - Feb 2014

Serving as Chief Operations Officer and Director with area responsibility of Scandinavia and South America and a supporting role for EU and Africa, as well as shareholder of Ariana Investment Ltd, Ariana Aviation Ltd, Ariana Automotive Ltd, Ariana Energy Ltd, and Ariana Shipping Ltd. The companies are engaging in investment projects within the business areas, mainly based in the UK, but with global outreach. The major company, Ariana Investment Ltd, is acting as an investment and trade vehicle for international alternative investments.

# Cartesian Developments Ltd, Director and COO 2013 - present

Appointed as Chief Operations Officer and Director for CD Ltd, a UK based company working as a secondary level introducer/facilitator for trades and investment programs.

# 7260 Holdings Ltd, Director 2013 – present

One of three directors and owners of a holding company owning and managing a handful of businesses in the Midlands, United Kingdom. Most business is real estate oriented.

# FiveStar Home Improvements Ltd and Goods Direct Ltd. Director 2013

Director and co-owner of two construction and development companies based in Leicestershire, UK.

### Infinaglobal Investment Llc, Non-executive director 2013 – present

Responsible for compliance and investment facilitation for high-end clients for IGI, a Dubai based financial services company serving international clients with investments, loans, and project funding.

# Freelance international business developer 2008 – present

I am working with financial services, project development, funding, deals structuring, and conceptualizing. Focus is on Africa and infrastructure, always human-centered and in sustainability terms, but I have and have had assignments on all continents. My main current activities include, but are not limited to facilitation projects in the energy and mining sectors in Africa, consultancy work in the social development sector in Sweden, EU, and the US, development and ownership of ventures in consultancy, real estate, and mining in East Africa, as well as general business development in Chile.

Occasionally, I give lectures, courses and speeches on various themes, such as organizational development, leadership, corporate responsibility, African development, social entrepreneurship, and related matters.

# JDL Investment AB, Marketing Director 2005 – 2009; Partner 2007- 2009

Infrastructure development in emerging markets, with focus on ICT supported

development in Africa, Latin America and Asia. Have developed own computer brand and concept, as well as energy supply solutions, housing systems/construction, ICT infrastructure/connectivity, and business development with focus on sustainable social, environmental and economical development. Also active in industry and commodities development. Main client base governments and governmental institutions. Retired when company merged into other activities.

www.jdl.se

## CUT Computers Ltd, Marketing Director and Partner 2006 - 2008

Co-founder, co-owner, and responsible for market and external relations and sales. CUT Computers is a spin-off from JDL, with a line of sturdy, low-power, low-cost computers adapted for use in developing countries. Establishing manufacturing units in six developing countries, market in more than 50 countries globally. Retired when company merged into other activities.

www.cutcs.com

## CUT Future Solutions, Marketing Director and Partner 2006 – 2008

Co-founder, co-owner, and responsible for marketing. CUT Future Solutions is an incubator and think tank with the aim of putting world leading technologies into developing world hands. Retired when company merged into other activities. www.cut-fs.com

# World Computer Exchange and ICT4Africa 2002-2005

Founding executive director of two non-governmental organizations focusing on ICT related development activities in Africa and Asia. Working with volunteer programs, technology transfer, and development of learning institutions in 15 countries, mainly in sub-Saharan Africa. Area manager, responsible for international networking, sales, funding, and logistics and quality assurance.

### ideal, Founding partner and consultant 1998 – 2004

Business ethics and sustainable development consultancy, working with businesses, NGOs and the public sector in Sweden and internationally. Responsible for developing tools, implementing models, lecturing and training, as well as evaluations and reporting. International work in Eastern and Western Europe, Africa, Asia, and North America. Currently involved in business ventures as a partner in several countries such as China, Rwanda, Ghana, Eritrea, Ethiopia, and Bolivia.

www.ideal.se

#### Previous experience also include:

Worked with capacity building programs for use of ICTs as a tool for poverty reduction in collaboration with UN institutions, governments, NGOs and business sector. (1998-2003)

Project manager at Uppsala University Centre for Environmental and Development

Studies – a cross-disciplinary academic center offering courses and projects on sustainable development to university students. Responsible for partnership development, project activities, supporting structures, and information, as well as some lecturing. (1999-2000)

Project manager at Swedish Employer's Association: Responsible for creating viable links between universities and small and medium sized businesses, as well as other cross disciplinary partnership activities. (1997-1999)

Evaluator at the Swedish Agency for Higher Education: Quality assessment evaluation of Stockholm University. (1997)

Vice president; President of Educational Committee at Uppsala Student Union: Responsible for educational matters, serving in numerous boards and committees. As vice president, co-responsible for management of staff and finances. (1995-1997)

President of Business Liaisons at Uppsala School of Technology: Project manager for business/university exhibition. Head of business relations and external funding. (1993-1994)

# Education

Uppsala University, Social sciences. Majoring in Political Science, specializing in Development Studies 1993-1997

Uppsala University, Aquatic and Environmental Engineering 1991-1997

High school, Natural Sciences, Ludvika, Sweden 1988-1991

# General information

Enjoy travelling; outdoors activities such as hiking and sailing; reading; cooking; house renovating; and spending time with family and friends. Also active in community development organizations, such as local yachting club, and local residential organization, as well as local oenology association. Enjoy to follow sports, and then mostly football (soccer), alpine and cross-country skiing, and track and fields. Also very interested in keeping track of current affairs internationally.

Born August 6, 1972 in Hongkong (now China), Swedish citizen (passport 86033919). Raised in the Middle East, East Africa, and Sweden. I live together with my wife and life partner Yuviza, and three kids (two girls, one boy: Franiza, 22, Carolina, 18, and Dante, 14). We also have three dogs and one cat, all rescued from the streets and brought back to a good life.

Currently resides in Chile (San Felipe, V. Region, Valparaiso) and the United Kingdom (Midlands, one hour north of London). The family also has a base in Stockholm, Sweden. Have been living in shorter or longer periods in England, the Netherlands, Ethiopia, and South Africa, among other countries.

### Languages

|         | Speak         | Understand    | Write         | Read          |
|---------|---------------|---------------|---------------|---------------|
| Swedish | Mother tongue | Mother tongue | Mother tongue | Mother tongue |
| English | Fluently      | Fluently      | Fluently      | Fluently      |
| Spanish | Good          | Very good     | Fair          | Very good     |
| French  | Fair          | Very good     | Good          | Very good     |
| German  | Some          | Very good     | Good          | Very good     |
| Italian | Some          | Good          | Some          | Good          |

#### Other

Fluent in all necessary computer software for normal business use and communication. Standard driver's licence.

### **APPENDIX**

### Additional information

### Personal qualities

Very dedicated, serial social entrepreneur. Strong international experience with vast network in developing countries, having worked in more than 35 countries globally. Appreciated lecturer. Proven track record on developing concepts, organizations, and people. Good writing, networking and communication skills.

Currently involved in a number of start-ups focusing on financial development, funding solutions and tools for human development. Numerous board assignments, currently mostly in private enterprises in the UK, Sweden, the Netherlands, China, and in several African countries.

### Assignments, selected

Advisor, UWIN project, MIT Media Lab, Boston, USA.

Think tank member, The Swedish Institute of International Affairs.

Member of United Nations ICT Task Force, working group for connectivity and access.

Advisor, Synapse Center, Dakar, Senegal.

Advisor, Boa Business Group, Abidjan, Cote d'Ivoire.

Advisor, GhaNordic, Ghana.

Co-founder and board member, SVEA Business Group, Ethiopia.

Co-founder and board member, SWEET Housing Business, Ethiopia.

### Memberships, selected

Founders Alliance, OpenBusinessCommunity

#### Numerous previous board assignments, selected

Uppsala University Library Board, Uppsala University Quality Assessment Board, Uppsala University Disciplinary Committee, National Association of Students, Educational Committee

#### Publications, selected

"The good company" (Swedish), 2006-2011 (forthcoming) Numerous articles in national and local printed and electronic media

Printed reports in Swedish and English:

Swedish – African Trade, an assessment for strengthening the ties, 2009.

The conflict of Sudan, and identifying ways forward, 2008.

Private sector development in East Africa, 2007.

Swedish Higher Education Institutions and the Environment - Assessment Report,

Swedish Ecodemics, 2004.

Evaluation of InterAction, a development project in five developing countries, LSU, 2003.

Educating for Sustainable Development, 2001.

Organizational behaviour, Sigtuna Foundation, 2000.

Democracy and its Critics, Uppsala Student Union, 1998.

Students and SMEs, Swedish Employer's Association, 1998.

The Role of Student Unions, Uppsala University, 1998.

Students as a Resource, Uppsala University, 1997.

### Conference contributions, selected

Alternative investment strategies for sustainable development, Geneva, Switzerland, December 2012.

Funding models for the 21st century, Amsterdam, Holland, November 2012.

Developing the East African Mining Sector, Addis Ababa, Ethiopia, February 2010.

Commodity Trade Development, Washington D.C., USA, June 2009.

L'Afrique emergente, Abidjan, Cote d'Ivoire, June 2009.

CSR and Private Sector Contribution's, Stockholm, Sweden, June 2008.

Private Sector's Role in Development (keynote), Johannesburg, South Africa, May 2008.

Telemedicine as a National Strategy (keynote), Addis Ababa, Ethiopia, May 2008.

Technologies for Rural Development Strategies, New York City, USA, October 2007.

Post-conflict strategies for sustainable development, Goma, DRC, July 2007.

Technology for Development, Kigali, Rwanda, July 2007.

Technologies as a tool for social and economic development, Dalian, China, August 2006.

Post-conflict strategies for sustainable development, Juba, South Sudan, July 2006.

Internet Governance workshop, Uppsala, Sweden, October 2005.

World Summit on the Information Society, Accra, Ghana, February 2005.

Tanzania eSchool workshop, Dar es Salaam, Tanzania, January 2005.

Strategy workshop SchoolNet Africa (session chair), Johannesburg, South Africa, Oct 2004.

ICTs for poverty reduction (session chair), Uppsala University, Sweden, September 2004.

Corporate Social Responsibility in practice, Stockholm, Sweden, March 2004.

World Summit on the Information Society, Geneva, Switzerland, December 2003.

Volunteerism and Human Capacity Building in the Information Society (session chair), Dakar, Senegal, October 2003.

First Mile Access (Sida and UNICT Taskforce), Kista, Sweden, June 2003.

ICTs in African Schools, Gaborone, Botswana, April 2003.

Education and environmental awareness, Baltic21 meeting for Ministers of Education, Haga Castle, Stockholm Sweden, April 2000.

Student Democracy and Development of a Nation, Asmara, Eritrea, March 1998.

Student Democracy as a Tool for Social Development, Nijmegen, Holland, May 1997.

Nobel Laureates Welcome Address, Stockholm/Uppsala, Sweden, December 1996.

References can be submitted upon request. Looking forward to your favourable reply and future discussions.

Burbage, UK, San Felipe, Chile and Stockholm, Sweden, May 12, 2014.

Johan Holmberg

Contact details:

E-mail: johan.o.holmberg@gmail.com

Phone: +56-9-52505076 (Chile)

+44-7887476007 (UK)

+46-769251375 (Sweden)

Viber: +56952505076 Whatsapp: +56952505076

Skype: johanholmberg1972

Address: O'Higgins 460

La Orilla

Putaendo, Region Valparaiso

CHILE Chile